Inventory of the W. W. Morrison Papers, 1804-1977
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
W. W. Morrison papers
1804-1977
Morrison, W.W. (William Wayne)
00323
30.89 cubic ft. (31 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Maps, photographs, diaries, transcripts, research notes, and other materials relating to emigration on the Overland Trails in the U.S. West.
Biography of W.W. Morrison
William Wayne Morrison (1898-1977) was passenger agent of the Union Pacific Railroad and also a historian of emigrant trails and pioneer graves.
Scope and Content
Collection contains materials collected by Morrison for his research on emigrant trails and grave sites in the Western United States. Included are transcripts of diaries and narratives of emigrants, photographs of gravesites, research materials, and secondary sources.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by W. W. Morrison at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
Received from W.W. Morrison in July 1986.
Access Terms
Trails -- United States.; Overland journeys to the Pacific.; Frontier and pioneer life -- West (U.S.);; Overland Trails.; Diaries.
Railroads; Immigration and American Expansion; Overland Journeys to the Western United States; Pioneers
Container List
- Artifacts, no dates (Box 1)
  - Leather file case, 1 item
  - Paperweights, Pattison grave stone replicas, rock, 3 items
  - Railroad hardware, spike, weight, unidentified, 3 items
  - Telegraph keys, demonstration models, 2 items
- Biographical Information, 1884-1977, William Wayne Morrison, b. April 8, 1898-d. March 7, 1977; telegrapher, freight and passenger agent for Union Pacific in Wyoming; historian of emigrant trails and pioneer graves (Box 1)
  - Morrison Family genealogical research and real estate matters; includes correspondence, photocopies of legal documents, etc., 1884-1972, 1 file
  - School & Personal, includes graduation programs, draft cards, newspaper clippings, biographical articles, etc., 1914-1976, 1 file
  - Employment & Financial, includes correspondence, employment contracts, schedules, employment history, bank records, 1914-1967, 1 file + 2 rolls
  - Membership cards, licenses and railroad passes of W.W. Morrison, Mildred Leachman Morrison (wife) and Wayne, Weldon and Wanda Morrison, 1920-1975, 151 items in 1 small box
- Correspondence Files, 1900-1978 (Box 1)
  - Union Pacific employment, letters of commendation and appreciation, 1925-1957, 1 file
  - Personal, copies of letters from Morrison to friends and family members regarding his activities, 1969-1977, 3 files
  - Miscellaneous, letters to and from Ruth Louise Johnson, Caroline Bancroft, various historical societies, etc., 1930-1978, 1 file
  - Post Cards, picturing Ohio, Wyoming and the west, Europe, Hawaii and New Zealand, some with messages, 1900-1974, 4 files
- Diaries, Narratives, Histories, 1805-1890 (Box 2)
  By or about western emigrants, including autobiographies, family histories, letters, transcripts from books and journals; typescripts unless otherwise noted
  - Bibliography, 1 file
  - Index, arranged by year of emigration 1805-1877, hand-written
  - Cecelia Emily McMillen Adams, 1852
  - Inez Eugenia Adams (Parker), 1848-1868
  - James Akin Jr., 1852, photocopy and typescripts
  - O. Allen, from Guide Book and Map to the Gold Fields of Kansas & Nebraska and Great Salt Lake City, 1859, photocopy
  - Henry Allyn, 1853
  - William M. Anderson, 1834
  - Susan P. Angell, 1852
  - Jesse Applegate, from Way Bill from Fort Hall to Willamette Valley, 1848
  - Malinda J. Armstrong, 1852
  - John Ball, 1832
  - Welborn Beeson, 1853
  - Maria A. Parsons Belshaw, 1853
  - Virginia Belle Benton, 1881
  - Mary Gibbs Bigelow, 1811-1845
  - Birmingham Emigrant Company Guide, by Leander V. Loomis, 1850
  - Patrick Breen, 1846
  - J. Goldsborough Bruff, from Gold Rush, 1849
  - Edwin Bryant, from What I Saw in California, 1846, 2 files
  - Jane Burnside, 1847
  - John Bratt, from Trails of Yesterday, 1865-1878
  - William A. Carter, 1857
  - Andrew J. Chambers, from Crossing the Plains in 1845
  - W.W. Chapman, 1849
  - Bennett C. Clark, 1849
  - William Clayton, 1847, published pamphlet
  - Daniel Benjamin Cleghorn, 1861
  - E.W. Conyers, 1852
  - Lt. Col. Philip St. George Cooke report, 1857
  - Paul Crandall and family, family history including partial diary of Polly Crandall Coon, 1852
  - Jesse W. Crosby, 1845-1850, publication & typescript
  - James C. David, 1852
  - Davis, 1852
  - Allan Jones Davis, 1842
  - Daniel Delany and family, 1843
  - Albert Jerome Dickson, from Covered Wagon Days, 1860's
  - Eliza P. Donner (Houghton), The Expedition of the Donner Party and Its Tragic Fate (1911), 1846, 2 files
  - Donner Miscellany (1947), includes diaries and other documents relating to the Donner Party, 1846
  - Dorion family, 1811-1850
  - Myra F. Eells, 1838
  - William A. Empey and Appleton M. Harmon (while keeping the Mormon ferry on the North Platte River), 1847
  - Eneas Entz, 1852
  - Elijah Bryan Farnham, 1849
  - Deerin Farrer, 1868
  - W.G. Felton, 1876-1877
  - Amanda Mary Fletcher, 1865
  - George W. Fox, 1866
  - Gabriel Franchere, from Narrative of a Voyage to the Northwest Coast of America, 1811-1814
  - Polly Frazier (Lewis), 1843
  - Caroline Gale (Budlong) and family, 1853-1886
  - Rev. A.E. Garrison, 1846
  - Orange Gaylord, 1850 & 1853, 2 files
  - Vincent Geiger and Wakeman Bryarly, 1849
  - John McTurk Gibson, 1859
  - Washington Smith Gilliam, 1844-1847
  - Augusta Winters Grant, 1856-1903
  - Mary Augusta Dix Gray, 1838-1842
  - William Henry Gray, 1838
  - Amelia Hadley, 1851
  - Gen. W.S. Harney, documents regarding battle of Ash Hollow, 1855, photocopies
  - Jesse Harritt, 1845
  - Loren B. Hastings, 1947
  - Lucy Ann Henderson (Deady), 1846
  - Randall H. Hewitt, from Across the Plains and Over the Divide, 1862
  - John Birney Hill, 1850
  - Celinda E. Himes, 1853
  - George H. Himes, 1853
  - Hines, from Oregon, Its History, Condition and Prospects, 1839
  - Silas L. Hopper, 1863
  - Hosea B. Horn, from Overland Guide, 1850
  - Lester Hulin, 1847
  - Homon Munson Humphrey, 1852
  - G.W. Hunt and family, "To Oregon By Ox-Team In '47", pamphlet by F. Lockley, 1847-1850, 2 copies
  - Christina Coutts Hunter, 1864
  - Lucy A. Ide, 1878
  - John T. Kearns, 1852
  - William Keil and wagon train, from Bethel and Aurora by R.J. Hendricks, 1855
  - William Claborn Kennedy, 1852
  - Amelia Stewart Knight, 1853
- Diaries, Narratives, Histories, 1805-1890 (Box 3)
  - William Lanford, 1850
  - Sarah L. Larimer, My Capture and Escape, or Life Among the Sioux (1869), 1864
  - John Doyle Lee, The Mormon Menace by A.H. Lewis (1904), 1857-1877, 2 files
  - Heinrich Leinhard, from Overland to Oregon, 1843
  - Reuben Lewis, 1842
  - Mary Jane Long, 1852
  - James Longmire, 1853
  - Leander V. Loomis, Birmingham Emigrating Company, 1850
  - Jesse Looney, 1843
  - Cyrus C. Loveland, 1850
  - Sam May, 1848
  - Dr. David S. Maynard, 1850
  - Rev. John McAllister, 1852
  - E.S. McComas, from A Journal of Travel, 1862
  - Martha Wilson McGregor, 1886
  - Byron McKinstry, 1850
  - Jack McNemee and family, 1845-1849
  - Ezra Meeker, from Ventures and Adventures, 1852
  - Howard Michael, 1863-1876
  - Joaguin Miller, from Overland in a Covered Wagon, 1854
  - James Knox Polk Miller, from The Road to Virginia City, 1864
  - Mormon emigration, from diaries and letters of Orson Pratt, Wilford Woodruff, George A. Smith, William Clayton, Thomas Bullock, Erastus Snow, Howard Egan, Norton Jacob, W.I. Appleby, Orson Hyde, Thomas Steed; 1847 & 1849, 1 scrapbook of newspaper clippings + 1 file
  - Asahel Munger and wife, 1839
  - Joseph Myers, 1860
  - Nathaniel Myers, 1853
  - Peter Skene Ogden, 1825-1827
  - Henry Page letters, also diary extracts of Joseph Hackney and E.I. Bowman, 1849
  - Joel Palmer, from Journal of Travels Over the Rocky Mountains, 1845-1846
  - Samuel Parker, 1845
  - Rev. Edward Evans Parrish, 1844
  - Sgt. Isaac B. Pennick, from The Bozeman Trail by Hebard & Brininstool, 1865, regarding Platte Bridge fight
  - Jake Pennock, of the 11th Kansas Cavalry, 1865, regarding Platte Bridge fight
  - Elisha Douglas Perkins, 1849-1850
  - Edwin Pettit, 1846-1851, printed
  - Capt. John Wolcott Phelps, 1857
  - Levi and A.J. Powell letters, 1870-1876
  - Orson Pratt, 1847
  - Virgil K. Pringle, 1846
  - John Pulsipher, 1857-1858, regarding Mormon War
  - Maj. P.B. Reading, 1843
  - James Frazier Reed, 1846
  - Joseph Rhodes, 1850
  - James Richey and family, 1852, photocopy & typescript
  - Albert D. Richardson, from Beyond the Mississippi, 1859
  - Capt. B.F. Rockafellow, 1865
  - Benjamin Williams Ryan, 1864
  - Rufus B. Sage, from Rocky Mountain Life, 1841-1843
  - Catherine Sager (Pringle), 1844-1847, 2 files
  - Matilda J. Sager (Delaney), 1844-1862
  - Scott family: John Tucker Scott and Abigail Scott (Duniway), 1852
  - Cornelia A. Sharp, 1852
  - Joe E. Sharp, 1852
  - William Shaw, 1844
  - William K. Sloan, 1853
  - Asa Bowen Smith, 1838
  - E. Willard Smith, 1839-1840
  - Elizabeth Dixon Smith (Geer), 1847
  - Moses Ira Smith, 1847
  - Sarah Gilbert White Smith, 1838
  - William Snow, 1850
  - Eliza Hart Spalding, 1836
  - Willis Spear, 1883
  - Howard Stansbury, from Exploration and Survey of the Valley of the Great Salt Lake of Utah, 1849
  - Agnes Stewart, 1853
  - Francher Stimson, 1850
  - Henry Atkinson Stine, 1850
  - Granville Stuart, 1852
  - Robert Stuart, 1812-1813
- Diaries, Narratives, Histories, 1805-1890 (Box 4)
  - J. Quinn Thornton, from Oregon and California, 1846, includes account of the Donner Party, 2 files
  - Charles Tinker, 1849
  - Henry Smith Turner, 1847
  - Elkanah Walker, 1838
  - Mary Richardson Walker (combined with Myra Eells), 1838
  - Rev. A.F. Waller, 1839-1840
  - Kimball Webster, from The Gold Seekers of '49
  - Dr. Marcus Whitman, 1835-1836
  - Narcissa Prentiss Whitman, 1836
  - Whitman Massacre reports, from Early Labors of the Missionaries (1903)
  - Henry T. Williams, from Pacific Tourist Guide, 1876
  - Joseph Williams, 1841-1842
  - Velina A. Williams, 1853
  - Margaret Windsor (Iman), 1852-1856
  - John Wood, 1850
  - John Work, 1830
  - Mabel Young (Sanborn), includes personal recollections of Brigham Young, 1863-1930, hand-written & typescript
  - Will H. Young, 1865
  - John S. Zieber, 1851
- Manuscripts, 1947-1974 (Box 4)
  By W.W. Morrison, written for classes, as letters, for newspaper publication, or as speeches
  - Autobiographical
    - English Compositions, stories written for class at Laramie Community College, Cheyenne, Wyoming, 1974
      - "A Kind Pen Friend" (Corajean Thornton)
      - "The Place Where I Was Born"
      - "Waikiki Beach"
      - "Jealousy"
      - "The Unicorn In The Garden"
      - Untitled & Exercises
    - "Eulogy To A Country School House, Near Cumberland, Ohio", 1967
    - "Eulogy To My Mother", 1947
    - "Home And The Back Door", 1965
    - "Little Rebecca Arrives/Bob And His New Dog/The White Doves", 1966
    - Travels
      - European Trip, 1964
      - Hawaii, 1967
      - Our Trips - Hawaii, West Virginia, Ohio, 1968
      - Puerto Vallarta, Mexico, 1970
      - Olympia, Washington, 1971
      - Our Trip - Ohio, 1973
    - "An Unforgettable Tragedy", no date
  - Ah-Ho-Appa, Chief Spotted Tail's Daughter, 1947
  - Pearl Bryan's Murder 1897, includes photographs, 1955
  - Custard Massacre at Platte Bridge Station, no date
  - Davis Ridge School House, Near Caldwell, Ohio, includes correspondence, newspaper clipping of published story, photographs, 1973
  - Grattan Massacre at Fort Laramie, 1953, 1969 and undated, 3 files
  - Mary Homsley's Grave, 1969 and undated, 2 files
  - Little Mary Kelly's Grave (Massacre of the Kelly-Larimer Train), 1949, 1954 and undated, 3 files
  - Emly Patrick's Grave, no date
  - Rachel Pattison's Grave, includes photographs, 1948 and undated, 2 files
  - Pattison Lake, Washington, and the Pattison Family, includes photographs, 1952, 4 files
  - The Pioneer Minister, no date
  - Rock Creek Methodist Church, Clackamus County, Oregon, includes photographs, 1950
  - Ann Rutledge And Lincoln, includes notes, correspondence, 1959
  - Telegraphy, includes clippings from printed sources, 1973
  - Early Roads In And Across Wyoming by L.C. Bishop, 1955
  - Fetterman Massacre by L.C. Bishop, 1959
- Photographic Files, 1840's-1970's (Box 5)
  - Positives
    - People & Graves
      - Ah-Ho-Appa (Falling Leaf) grave and family: Chief Spotted Tail and wife
      - Samuel K. Barlow grave, Barlow Toll Gate
      - Floyd D. Bryan grave and Hilo, Hawaii
      - Pearl Bryan grave, family graves, and Greencastle, Indiana
      - Mrs. S. Chambers grave, Mr. and Mrs. Andrew J. Chambers
      - William L. Clary grave
      - J.A. Deaton and wife
      - Donner Party: Donners, Graveses, Reeds, Sarah Keyes grave
      - Lucinda Eubank (Atkinson) grave and family graves: Eubank, Frogue, Atkinson, Pollard
      - Belle and Cary Eubank, Dannie Marble and Laura Roper
      - John C. Friend
      - Henry Hill grave
      - Nancy Hill grave
      - Mary E. Homsley grave and family: husband, daughters, sister, and descendents; Homsley, Gibson, Taylor, White, Oden, Wells, Jenkins
      - John Hunton and wife
      - Indians: Chief Joseph with Gen. Gibbon; Chief High Eagle; monuments to Keokuk and Winema; unidentified
      - Elva Ingram grave and family: parents, brothers and sisters, cousins; Ingram and Richey, Richey cabins
      - Rev. Clinton Kelly
      - Kelly-Larimer Indian captivity: Little Boxelder massacre site, graves of Mary Kelly and Sharp-Taylor-Franklin, Sarah L. Larimer, Fanny Kelly and grave
      - Ada Magill grave and family: parents, brothers and sisters and descendants; Magill, Mahan, Cunningham
      - Ezra Meeker and grave
      - J.P. Parker grave
      - Emly Patrick grave
      - Rachel Pattison grave and family graves: Davis, Pattison, Thornton
      - C.B. Platt grave
      - J.R. Powell and Mary Powell Roush
      - William Reynolds and Dr. Ellis Reynolds Shipp
      - Lucinda Rollins grave
      - Matilda J. Sager (Delaney)
      - John Tucker Scott
      - Sarah W. Smith
      - A.H. Unthank and grave, O.B. Unthank, O.N. Unthank
      - Mary Richardson Walker
      - Rebecca Winters grave and family: husband, sons, descendants; Winters, Grant, Bennion
      - Rebecca Winters grave dedication, special train
      - Mabel Young (Sanborn), Lucy Sanborn Spencer
      - Miscellaneous people: Billy the Kid and grave, Richard Clark ("Deadwood Dick"), Mariano Medina
      - Other graves: Thomas Mastin, Charles Hatch, William Durham and I.M. Mead, Jo Barnette and Mrs. Bryan, Barr-Mason-Morgan, T.P. Baker, Nancy Hanks Lincoln, Gladys Mary Fletcher, Otter Woman ("Sacajawea"), William Guerrier, 2 unidentified
      - Morrison family and friends or unidentified, 1 file + 1 oversize portrait
    - Oregon Trail sites
      - Scottsbluff to Fort Laramie: monuments at Scottsbluff, Chimney Rock, Robidoux Pass, South Torrington, Grattan Massacre site, etc., 3 files
      - Fort Laramie: sketches, copies of 1870's and 1880's photos, pre-restoration, and post-restoration
      - Fort Laramie to Horse Shoe Station: Guernsey trail ruts, Porter's Rock, etc., 2 files
      - Horse Shoe Station to Fort Casper: LaPrele Station, Ralston Baker grave, Deer Creek Station sketch, Jim Bridger Ferry monument, Horse Creek Station site, Fort Bernard site, 2 files
      - Fort Casper to South Pass: Custard Massacre site, Independence Rock, Devil's Gate and Split Rock, Martin's Cove monument, South Pass City
      - Oregon and Overland Trails through Nebraska and Wyoming, 3 files
      - Oregon Trail in Oregon, near John Day River
      - Applegate Road
    - States
      - California: Donner Party camp sites, San Francisco, unidentified, 2 files
      - Colorado: Gunnison, U.S. Stage Line Schedule
      - Nebraska: Kimball
      - Ohio: Archer's Ridge School House, Cumberland School House, Davis Ridge School House, 3 files
      - Oregon: Rock Creek Methodist Church, homes, buildings, cemeteries, people, etc., 3 files
      - Utah: Salt Lake City
      - Washington: Pattison Lake, Fort Walla Walla, Whitman Mission site, Pioneer Cemetery, Olympia, Fort Nisqually, etc., 4 files
      - Wyoming:, 5 files
        - Cheyenne
        - Hillsdale depot 1927, with Mr. and Mrs. W.W. Morrison and colleagues
        - Teepee Rings, north of Pinebluffs
        - Telegraph Demonstration at the State Museum in Cheyenne, 1976
        - Trains, Sherman Station, Dale Creek Bridge, etc.
    - Unidentified and miscellaneous buildings, structures, landmarks, etc.
  - Negatives
    - People & Graves
      - Ah-Ho-Appa grave and family
      - Ralston Baker grave
      - Samuel K. Barlow grave
      - Floyd Bryan grave and Hilo, Hawaii
      - Pearl Bryan grave and Greencastle, Indiana
      - William L. Clary grave
      - Donner Party
      - John C. Friend
      - Robert Harvey
      - Henry Hill grave
      - John Hollman grave
      - Mary Homsley grave and family
      - Indians and soldiers: Chief Charlot, Chief Joseph, Gen. Gibbon, and others
      - Indian Women: Mary Crow, Margaret Red Deer, Pendleton Indian queen
      - Elva Ingram grave and family, Richey family
      - Sanford and Nancy Johnson, and Nancy Johnson Green
      - A. Kelly grave
      - Rev. Clinton Kelly
      - Kelly-Larimer Indian captivity, Little Boxelder massacre site and graves
      - Amanda Lamin grave
      - Ada Magill grave and family
      - J.P. Parker grave
      - Emly Patrick grave
      - Rachel Pattison grave and family
      - Portugee Phillips grave
      - C.B. Platt grave
      - J.R. Powell and Mary Powell Roush
      - Dr. Ellis Reynolds (Shipp)
      - Lucinda Rollins grave
      - Matilda J. Sager (Delaney)
      - John Tucker Scott
      - A.H. Unthank and grave and family
      - Mabel Young (Sanborn)
      - W.W. Morrison and family
      - School groups; West Virginia; family friends
- Photographic Files, 1840's-1970's (Box 6)
  - Negatives
    - States
      - California: Donner Party camp sites
      - Illinois: Nauvoo and Brigham Young home
      - Nebraska:
        - Ash Hollow and area
        - Blue Water battle ground
        - Chimney Rock
        - Courthouse and Jail Rocks
        - Kimball
        - Scottsbluff and area
      - Ohio: Davis Ridge School House, Archer's Ridge School House
      - Oregon: homes, Rock Creek Methodist Church, monuments, towns, landmarks, etc., 3 files
      - Utah: first house in Salt Lake City
      - Washington:
        - Pattison Lake
        - Fort Walla Walla
        - Whitman Mission site
        - Fort Nisqually, Crosby House, Olympia, etc.
      - Wyoming:
        - Bridger Ferry
        - Cheyenne Airport
        - Custard Massacre site
        - Devil's Gate and Split Rock
        - Emigrant Laundry Tub
        - Fort Bernard
        - Fort Casper
        - Fort Laramie
        - Grattan Massacre site
        - Guernsey trail ruts
        - Horse Shoe Station
        - Independence Rock
        - LaGrange
        - Porter's Rock
        - Register Cliff
        - South Torrington, William Guerrier grave
        - Teepee Rings, north of Pinebluffs
        - Trek, 1953
        - Warm Springs trail ruts
  - Printing Mats
    - Mary and Ben Homsley graves, 3 items
    - Fanny Kelly
    - Rachel Pattison grave, William and Mary Pattison, Pattison Lake map, 5 items
    - W.W. Morrison, Mildred Morrison, and Wanda Mae
    - Grattan Massacre site
    - Guernsey trail ruts
    - Rock Creek Methodist Church, 4 items
- Research Files, 1945-1976 (Box 6)
  Includes correspondence, newspaper clippings, transcripts from published sources, etc.
  - Graves: investigations of burials along the Oregon Trail, including correspondence with descendants and family histories
    - Ah-Ho-Appa (Falling Leaf) 1866, includes notes on and family histories of Spotted Tail, High Eagle, and other Sioux and Cheyenne, 1948-1973, 2 files
    - Floyd Bryan 1912, correspondence regarding his death in Hawaii, 1968
    - Mary Homsley 1852, and Homsley, Gibson, Oden, Taylor families, 1946-1976, 2 files
    - Elva Ingram 1852, and Ingram, Akin, Richey families, 1945-1976, 3 files
    - Sanford Johnson 1850, and Johnson, Green, Damon families, 1948-1951
    - A. Kelly and John Hollman 1852, 1946-1949
    - Amanda Lamin 1850, 1946-1972
    - Ada Magill 1864, and Magill, Gregg, Laughlin, Cunningham families, 1946-1975
- Research Files, 1944-1977 (Box 7)
  - Graves: investigations of burials along the Oregon Trail, including correspondence with descendants and family histories
    - Rachel Morgan 1847, and Morgan, Woodsides families, 1957-1973
    - J.P. Parker 1860, 1946-1950
    - Rachel Pattison 1849, and Pattison, Davis, Warren, Wyllie families; also Robert C. Wyllie in Hawaii and Pattison donation land claims near Olympia, Washington, 1945-1976, 9 files
    - Lucinda Rollins 1849, 1945-1955
    - Alva H. Unthank 1850, and Unthank family, 1944-1963
    - Rebecca Winters 1852, and Winters, Burdick families; also "The Life Story of Augusta Winters Grant" by Mary Grant Judd, clippings and transcript from newspaper publication, 1945-1951, 4 files
  - Indian Massacres and Indian Captivities: including correspondence with descendants and family histories
    - Lucinda Walton Eubank 1864, Eubank-Roper Indian captivity and Eubank, Frogue, Atkinson, Roper families, 1972-1977, 3 files
    - Amanda Mary Fletcher 1865, Indian captivity and Fletcher, Cook families, 1972-1976
    - John Lawrence Grattan 1854, Grattan Massacre and Grattan family, 1946-1972
- Research Files, 1946-1977 (Box 8)
  - Indian Massacres and Indian Captivities: including correspondence with descendants and family histories
    - Fanny Kelly 1864, Indian captivity with Sarah L. Larimer and Kelly, Wiggins families, 1946-1977, 2 files
    - Whitman Massacre 1847, includes transcripts of Early Labors of the Missionaries (1903) and narratives of survivors Catherine Sager, Matilda Sager and Nathan Kimball, 1948-1954, 4 files
  - Other People
    - Calamity Jane Canary, and Canary family, 1948
    - Donner Party 1846, and Donner, Reed families; also transcripts of Grim Journey (1934) by H. Birney, History of the Donner Party (1879) by C.F. McGlashen, Donner Miscellany (1947), Breen and Reed diaries and various other published sources, 9 files
    - Silver Dollar Tabor, daughter of H.A.W. Tabor, also Leadville and the Tabor family
    - Mormons: Nauvoo, emigration, Mountain Meadows Massacre, etc. 1952-1972, 4 files
  - Oregon Trail: investigations of the route, landmarks, graves and events, 1945-1973
    - St. Louis to St. Joseph: illness on the trail; methods of transportation; early railroads; early history
    - Missouri River to Big Blue: grave of Mrs. Keyes; Alcove Springs; Kansas, etc.
    - Big Blue to Platte Junction: Eubank-Roper Indian captivity; graves of George Winslow, Susan Haile; Fort Kearney; Cottonwood Spring; Fort McPherson, etc.
    - Platte Junction to Ash Hollow: California Crossing; Julesberg; Indian Wars and Harney Massacre; graves of John Hollman, Rachel Pattison, etc.
    - Ash Hollow to Scottsbluff: graves of George W. Tindal, Rachel Pattison, A. Kelly; Courthouse and Jail Rocks; Chimney Rock, etc.
- Research Files, 1945-1973 (Box 9)
  - Oregon Trail: investigations of the route, landmarks, graves and events
    - Scottsbluff: Hiram Scott; grave of John Dunn; Robideaux Pass, etc.
    - Scottsbluff to Grattan Massacre: Fort Mitchell; graves of Henry & Louise Williams, Henry Hill, William Clary; Horse Creek Treaty, etc.
    - Grattan Massacre to Fort Laramie: Fort Laramie Treaty 1851, etc.
    - Fort Laramie: from 1834-1890, 4 files